<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>videos on Stats of DOOM</title>
    <link>https://statisticsofdoom.com/tags/videos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in videos on Stats of DOOM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>buchananlab@gmail.com (statstools.com)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>buchananlab@gmail.com (statstools.com)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://statisticsofdoom.com/tags/videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plan for Open Access Updates</title>
      <link>https://statisticsofdoom.com/post/a-plan-for-open-access-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (statstools.com)</author>
      <guid>https://statisticsofdoom.com/post/a-plan-for-open-access-updates/</guid>
      <description>So! Here&amp;rsquo;s the plan we are working on to update everything with official details:
 JASP + OSKB:  The JASP pages on OSF are all updated: https://osf.io/t56kg/ I have built the structure for the JASP page with the OSKB &amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s still pending as of October 12, but you will be able to find it at this link when they approve it: https://www.oercommons.org/courseware/lesson/73379 In discussions with the OSKB today, we are going to put together a few promotional materials to help everyone find the community including a paper for the JASP materials, a presentation at Midwestern Psychological Association, and a twitter poster for the Society of Teaching of Psychology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JASP Videos &#43; Guides</title>
      <link>https://statisticsofdoom.com/post/jasp-videos-guides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>buchananlab@gmail.com (statstools.com)</author>
      <guid>https://statisticsofdoom.com/post/jasp-videos-guides/</guid>
      <description>Hey everybody! I am back and finally getting to videos again. I hesistate to say “it’s been crazy!” because I feel like that’s always a thing that academics say, but I will say I’ve had a lot of life going on, and I am finally getting back to a normal amount of crazy.
I’ve decided to do some simple videos to start - so I am creating how-to videos to go with our JASP guides we created this summer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>